floridahospital.com 2012-08-19

# Privacy Policy | Florida Hospital

### 1994 – 1996

In 1994, Thomas Werner, then President of Florida Hospital, decided to organize these international medical programs totally in-house. SHARES International was created as an independent division within the Florida Hospital Foundation, Florida Hospital’s charitable arm. A year later, SHARES International launched its first international mission to Tanzania.

Florida Hospital and Adventist Health System appreciate your interest in our company and health care facilities. We urge you to read our Privacy Policy / Terms and Conditions of Use (“Privacy Policy”) to understand how we maintain and protect any information that you may give us through our website.  
Submission of information to our website means that you have agreed to abide by all of the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy.

### Information We Receive

The information we receive from users of our website can be categorized as being either anonymous, personally identifiable, or protected health information.

### Anonymous Information; Log Files

Anonymous information refers to information that cannot be tied to a specific individual. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and click stream data. Many persons who access our website do not use the personalization features or member services that are available to them through our website, and therefore these individuals are anonymous to us and the data we collect from them does not enable us to identify them in any personal way. For example, we may know that 5,000 users visit our website every day and that 3,000 of them reside in Florida, but we may not know their names or where they live. All anonymous information we collect through our website is collected when your web browser accesses our website. When you surf the Internet, your web browser automatically transmits information about your preferences to our server every time you visit our website. The anonymous information collected by us through your web browser helps us to monitor audience size, measure traffic patterns and identify popular services and information within our website. We use this information to improve our services to you and to help develop improved services based on user interests, behavior and demographics. We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable or protected health information.

### Personally Identifiable Information

Personally identifiable information refers to information that can be used to identify you, such as your name, address, age, etc. In many cases, we ask for this information to provide the personalization feature or member service you wish to use. The amount of personally identifiable information that we know about you is entirely up to you. We will only know personally identifiable information if you choose to share this information about yourself; however, some features or services may not be available unless we obtain a certain amount of personally identifiable information.

We collect personally identifiable information when you voluntarily provide it when, for example, requesting a newsletter that we produce, indicating that you would like to receive certain targeted information on topics that interest you, applying for classes or donating money through our on-line foundation.

### Protected Health Information

Protected health information, for purposes of this website, refers to the information you provide when, for example, you pay your health care bills online, make an appointment, or pre-register for a health care service, and is further explained under our Notice of Patient Privacy Practices.

### Cookies

In addition, we may also collect information through the use of "cookies". When you visit our website for the first time, our server sends a cookie to your computer's hard drive through your web browser. A cookie is a small text file that contains a unique identification number that is sent from us and stored on your computer. Cookies enable us to recognize your web browser whenever you visit our website through the unique identification number assigned to the cookie, and this information is stored to help facilitate your use of the website the next time you visit.

If you wish to find out how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to disable cookies altogether and how to monitor when you receive a new cookie, check the "help" feature of your web browser. However, not accepting or disabling cookies from our website may prevent you from accessing certain parts of our website.

### Disclosure of and Access to Information

### Anonymous and Personally Identifiable Information

We may share anonymous information with third parties. For example, we may match our user information, such as gender and age preferences and usage, with data of these third parties to help develop additional products and services to offer through our website. As a general rule, we will not disclose your personally identifiable information to any unaffiliated third party, except when we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we need to treat the information collected through this website as an asset in the event of the merger or sale of Adventist Health System, or a portion of our business. Your personally identifiable information may be accessed by our management information services team or an affiliated third party providing technical support or maintenance for us.

If we offer services using or in conjunction with an unaffiliated third party, we may need to share some or all of your personally identifiable information with that unaffiliated third party for purposes of providing the services to you. If you do not want your personally identifiable information to be shared, you can choose not to use that particular feature or service.

In some circumstances we may be required by law to disclose personally identifiable information. We will do so, in good faith, only to the extent we believe to be required by law. We may also disclose personally identifiable information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against a third party who may be violating our terms and conditions governing the use of our website, or who may be (intentionally or unintentionally) causing injury to or interference with your or our rights or property or those of a third party.

We reserve the right to treat anonymous and personally identifiable information collected through this website as an asset which may be transferred to a third party in connection with the merger or sale of Adventist Health System, or a portion of our business.

### Protected Health Information

The use and disclosure of protected health information is governed by the terms and conditions of our Notice of Patient Privacy Practices. With respect to use of this website, protected health information may be accessed by our management information services team or an affiliated third party providing technical support or maintenance for us. We reserve the right to treat protected health information collected through this website as an asset which may be transferred to a third party in connection with the merger or sale of Adventist Health System, or a portion of our business.

### Membership

To use the password-protected member services available on this website, you may choose to become a “member” by registering as a member. Upon registration you will be assigned a unique member username and a password for access to the password-protected member services. Your member username and password should be kept strictly confidential to prevent unauthorized use. You are responsible for safeguarding and maintaining the secrecy of your member username and password at all times. You agree to notify Adventist Health System promptly of any unauthorized use of your member username and password. You will remain liable for any use of the member services unless and until you notify Adventist Health System of the unauthorized use of your member username and password. Adventist Health System may suspend your membership without notice to you in the event that you do not use the website for an extended period of time.

In consideration of your membership, you agree to: (a) voluntarily provide true, accurate and current information about yourself; and (b) to maintain and update this personally identifiable or protected health information to keep it true, accurate and current. Adventist Health System reserves the right to approve any member before the member may use the password-protected member services.

If any information provided by you is untrue or inaccurate, Adventist Health System has the right to terminate your membership and refuse to provide you with use of the password-protected member services, without benefit of refund. You understand that Adventist Health System does not routinely perform background checks on members, and assumes no liability for the accuracy of the personally identifiable or protected health information provided.

### Security Measures

Adventist Health System has taken reasonable steps and has employed industry-standard practices and technology to ensure the integrity and confidentiality of personally identifiable and protected health information; but because even the most secure computer system can be violated, Adventist Health System cannot guarantee absolute security.

IMPORTANT: Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose information about yourself in the public domain, for example, through bulletin boards, chat rooms, e-mails, it is likely to be collected and used by third parties. These third parties may use your information to contact you or for unauthorized purposes. Also, please remember that no one can guarantee the absolute security of information transmitted electronically.

### Updating, Correcting and Deleting Personally Identifiable or Protected Health Information

We strongly believe in providing you with the ability to access, edit, or opt-out of providing personally identifiable or protected health information to us. Accordingly, at any time, you may amend, update or delete the information about you (or your child(ren)) contained in any registration profile you have completed with us, including any and all personally identifiable or protected health information, or stop receipt of a newsletter, by mailing your request to:

Adventist Health System  
111 North Orlando Avenue  
Winter Park, Florida 32789  
Attn: Data Security Officer

### Website Links

Our website may contain links to other sites. These links are for your convenience only, and Adventist Health System makes no representations or endorsements whatsoever regarding such other sites. You should review the privacy policies of other sites carefully before providing any information to such website. Adventist Health System is not responsible for the privacy policies or procedures or the content of any other website.

### Children Policy

Our website is not intended for use by children. Children under the age of 13 may only use our website under the supervision of a parent or guardian. The website is not directed at children under the age of 13. Adventist Health System complies with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) and does not knowingly permit registration or submission of personally identifiable or protected health information by anyone under 13 years of age. This age requirement is posted each time we request personally identifiable or protected health information.

Adventist Health System's Limited Warranties; Disclaimer of Liability; Indemnity by You  
ADVENTIST HEALTH SYSTEM DOES NOT MAKE ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, REPRESENTATIONS OR ENDORSEMENTS WHATSOEVER (INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, WARRANTIES OF TITLE OR NONINFRINGEMENT, OR THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE) REGARDING INFORMATION, CONTENT OR ITEMS APPEARING ON THIS WEBSITE. ADVENTIST HEALTH SYSTEM DOES NOT WARRANT THAT DOWNLOADS FROM THE WEBSITE WILL BE FREE OF ANY VIRUS, WORM, TROJAN HORSE OR OTHER DATA ALTERING OR CONTAMINATING COMPONENTS. YOU ARE RESPONSIBLE FOR ENSURING THAT YOU HAVE IMPLEMENTED PROCEDURES TO PREVENT SUCH CONTAMINATING COMPONENTS FROM INFECTING YOUR COMPUTER AND ITS DATA.

WHILE ADVENTIST HEALTH SYSTEM TRIES TO KEEP THE INFORMATION ON THIS WEBSITE BOTH ACCURATE AND UP-TO-DATE, ADVENTIST HEALTH SYSTEM DOES NOT WARRANT THE ACCURACY, COMPLETENESS, CORRECTNESS, USEFULNESS, OR APPLICABILITY OF ANY INFORMATION, OR OTHER DATA OR ITEMS APPEARING ON THIS WEBSITE. ADVENTIST HEALTH SYSTEM WILL NOT BE LIABLE IN ANY EVENT TO ANY USER OF THIS SERVICE FOR ANY DECISION MADE OR ACTION TAKEN IN RELIANCE UPON THE INFORMATION, CONTENT, OR OTHER ITEMS PRESENTED ON THIS WEBSITE.

IN NO EVENT SHALL ADVENTIST HEALTH SYSTEM BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, CONSEQUENTIAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, PUNITIVE, OR ANY OTHER MONETARY OR OTHER DAMAGES, FEES, FINES, PENALTIES, OR LIABILITIES ARISING OUT OF OR RELATING IN ANY WAY TO THIS WEBSITE, OR WEBSITES ACCESSED THROUGH THIS WEBSITE, AND/OR THEIR CONTENT OR INFORMATION. A USER'S SOLE AND EXCLUSIVE REMEDY FOR DISSATISFACTION WITH THE WEBSITE IS TO STOP USING THE WEBSITE.  
ADVENTIST HEALTH SYSTEM DOES NOT GUARANTEE CONTINUOUS OR UNINTERRUPTED ACCESS TO THIS WEBSITE, AND OPERATION OF THIS WEBSITE MAY BE INTERFERED WITH BY FACTORS BEYOND ADVENTIST HEALTH SYSTEM'S CONTROL.

YOU AGREE TO INDEMNIFY, DEFEND, AND HOLD ADVENTIST HEALTH SYSTEM HARMLESS, AS WELL AS ADVENTIST HEALTH SYSTEM'S OFFICERS, DIRECTORS, EMPLOYEES, AGENTS, INFORMATION PROVIDERS AND SUPPLIERS FROM AND AGAINST ALL LOSSES, EXPENSES, DAMAGES AND COSTS, INCLUDING REASONABLE ATTORNEY'S FEES, RESULTING FROM YOUR VIOLATION OF THESE CONDITIONS OF USE OR THE USE OF THIS SERVICE.

### Use of This Website Creates an Agreement

Your continued use of this website constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy forms an agreement that is entered into and is subject to the laws of the State of Florida. Those laws will apply, except the choice of law statutes, in construing and interpreting this agreement. If any provision of this agreement is held to be unenforceable, invalid, void or voidable, by a court or other tribunal of competent jurisdiction, then such provision shall be given a limited effect or shall be eliminated to the extent necessary so that the remaining provisions of this agreement remain in full force and effect.

### Prohibited Use of This Website

If you live in a state or country that has laws that would either (1) void or alter these terms and conditions or (2) make illegal the access or use of this website, then your use of this website is unauthorized; it cannot be sanctioned by Adventist Health System, and you use the website at your own risk.

### Disclaimer

This Privacy Policy only applies to information collected through this website. This Privacy Policy does not apply to personally identifiable information received or created by Adventist Health System from any of the following:

  * Online search and application for employment opportunities at Adventist Health System, other than physician career opportunities. These employment search activities are provided by a third-party website operator and subject to a separate privacy policy. If you wish to review the privacy policy which applies to online employment search and application, please see this webpage.
  * FHHS Member Services. If you wish to review the privacy policy which applies to FHHS Member Services, please see this webpage.
  * Florida Physicians Medical Group. If you wish to review the privacy policy which applies to Florida Physicians Medical Group, please see this webpage
  * Adventist Health System nursing homes.

### Contacting Us Regarding this Privacy Policy or the Website

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy or any other questions concerning the website, please contact:  
Adventist Health System  
111 North Orlando Avenue  
Winter Park, FL 32789  
Attn: Data Security Officer  
Phone: (407) 975-1400

### Changes to Privacy Policy

Adventist Health System may modify or change this Privacy Policy at any time. Such modifications or changes become effective immediately when they are posted to this website. You agree to review this Privacy Policy frequently so that you will be familiar with the terms. You further agree that each time you use this website that you are, by such use, consenting to the terms of this Privacy Policy that are applicable at your time of use.

###   
1997- 1999

SHARES International has evolved and matured over the years since its first program in 1995. In those early days, SHARES International helped send Family Practice Residents overseas to deliver basic health services in needy areas. Subsequently, a cleft lip and palate surgical and a physical therapy component was added in 1997.

### 2000 – 2005

In 2000, SHARES International re-focused its surgical program to the poorest southern states of Mexico. The SHARES International program became aware that the direct health services of three or four Family Practice Residents and one Faculty for five days a year in a state with 5 million people would not have much impact. However, paired with a Mexican public health doctor, our SHARES International team is helping to train the Mexican physicians in expanding techniques and services, a basic component of Mexico’s health reform.

### 2006 – 2010

SHARES International entered into a partnership with the state Secretariats of Health and the Plastic Surgeon on staff at the main public hospitals in Merida, Oaxaca, Villahermosa, Tuxtla Gutierrez and Veracruz, Mexico.

### 2011

In 2011, SHARES was a catalyst in establishing the first Cleft Lip and Palate Clinic in Merida, Mexico. As a result, the clinic is now providing medical and dental care to over 300 patients per month. The clinic is part of the Hospital General Agustin O’Horan in Merida. Dr. Maria Flores Mendez is the lead surgeon and clinic director.

### 2012

SHARES International is working with the local Mexican health authorities in these states to create cleft clinics that will insure that the best and most comprehensive services are provided to needy children throughout the year.
